Finding Aid for Business and Professional Women’s Club of Ann Arbor (Mich.) records, 1920-1988
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Business and Professional Women’s Club of Ann Arbor (Mich.) records 1920-1988
Business and Professional Women’s Club of Ann Arbor (Mich.)
1 oversize folders
6 linear feet
85508 Bk.2 2; UBKl
Correspondence, minutes, publications, membership lists, histories, scrapbooks, and photographs relating to club activities, especially state and national conventions, 1921-1966.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records came from the organization (donor no. 3608 ) and from Dr. Luella Cable (donor no. 4990 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
In the summer of 1921 several business women in Ann Arbor became interested in the National Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs and the Michigan Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs. They felt that there were enough women in the area engaged in business or occupying responsible positions to form a local club which would be federated with the state and national organizations. A preliminary meeting with seventy representative women was held. Then in November 1921, the Business and Professional Women's Club of Ann Arbor was established.
The record group is divided into the following series: Historical and Background Material; Correspondence and other papers; Meeting Minutes; Membership material; Programs and activities; District and state and national materials; Photographs; and Scrapbooks. There is one folder in the records relating to the organization's work on behalf of better housing in Ann Arbor, 1921-1922.
Subjects:
Dwellings--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Business and Professional Women's Club of Ann Arbor (Mich.); Housing--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Women--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Societies and clubs.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Business and Professional Women's Club of Ann Arbor (Mich.); Women--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Societies and clubs.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Historical / Background
  - Chapter histories 1923, 1924, 1929, 1951 notes (Box 1)
  - Constitutions and By-laws 1923-1959, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - Annual Officers reports 1967-1986 (Box 1)
  - Initiation ceremonies (Box 1)
  - Songs (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 1)
  - Tributes and memorials (Box 1)
- Correspondence and other papers 1920-1984
  - 1920s (Box 1)
  - 1920-1921 (Box 1)
  - 1922 (Box 1)
  - January-March, 1923 (Box 1)
  - April-August, 1923 (Box 1)
  - September-December, 1923 (Box 1)
  - January-September, 1924 (Box 1)
  - October-December, 1924 (Box 1)
  - 1925 (Box 1)
  - 1926 (Box 1)
  - 1927-1928 (Box 1)
  - 1929 (Box 1)
  - 1930-1932 (Box 1)
  - 1933-1936 (Box 1)
  - 1937-1939 (Box 1)
  - 1940-1949 (Box 1)
  - 1950-1954 (Box 1)
  - 1955-1956 (Box 1)
  - 1962-1967 (Box 1)
  - 1969-1984 (Box 1)
- Meeting minutes 1921-1986
  - 1921-1922 (Box 1)
  - 1923-1924 (Box 1)
  - 1925-1927 (Box 1)
  - 1928-1930 (Box 1)
  - 1931-1937 (Box 1)
  - 1946, 1951-1954 (Box 1)
    (include annual reports)
  - 1955-1960 (Box 2)
  - 1961-1962, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - 1963-1968 (Box 2)
  - 1974-1986 (Box 2)
- Membership material 1921-1986
  - Membership lists 1921-1930, 1965-1966 (Box 2)
  - Membership lists 1930-1966 (Box 2)
  - Membership lists 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Membership remittance summary and lists (Box 2)
- Programs and activities, 1921-1987
  - Publicity committee 1921-1924 (Box 2)
  - Local programs 1926-1930, 1934 (Box 2)
  - Civic participation 1921-1964 including material on the Swabian Dance Hall (Box 2)
  - Report on Ann Arbor Housing 1921-1922 scrapbook (Box 2)
  - Education 1923-1929 including essay "Value of a College Education for Women" (Box 2)
  - Good Will Tours 1928-1930 (Box 2)
  - Civil Defense 1950-1960 (Box 2)
  - Traffic Safety Conferences 1965 (Box 2)
  - Political interests, legislation 1922-1966, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Programs from Ann Arbor, state and national special events 1940-1987 (Box 2)
  - Press releases 1974-1976 (Box 2)
- District and state and national materials 1921-1967
  - District I 1931-1934 correspondence and annual reports (Box 2)
  - District II 1951-1957 correspondence and annual reports, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - District IX 1957-1962 meeting minutes and annual reports, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - District IX 1963-1967 meeting minutes and annual reports (Box 2)
  - Michigan Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs 1923-1966 annual reports and correspondence, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - The National Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs 1921-1962 annual reports, convention proceedings, 1952-1962, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Bulletins of sister Business and Professional Women's Clubs 1961-1962 (Box 3)
  - Washtenaw County Federation of Women's Clubs 1918-1964 (Box 3)
  - Various publications (Box 3)
- National and State conventions 1921-1966
  - National convention 1921 Cleveland, Ohio (Box 3)
  - National convention 1922 Chattanooga, Tennessee (Box 3)
  - State convention 1922 Flint (Box 3)
  - National convention 1923 Portland, Oregon (Box 3)
  - State convention 1923 Muskegon (Box 3)
  - National convention 1924 West Baden, Indiana (Box 3)
  - State convention 1924 Jackson (Box 3)
  - National convention 1925 Portland, Maine, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - State convention 1925 Muskegon (Box 3)
  - National convention 1926 Des Moines, Iowa (Box 3)
  - State convention 1926 Detroit (Box 3)
  - State board meeting 1926 Grand Rapids (Box 3)
  - National convention 1927 Oakland, California (Box 3)
  - State conventions 1927 (Box 3)
  - National conventions 1928 New Orleans, Louisiana (Box 3)
  - State convention 1928 Grand Rapids (Box 3)
  - National convention 1929 Mackinac Island, Michigan (Box 3)
  - National convention 1930 Chicago, Illinois (Box 4)
  - State convention 1930 Flint (Box 4)
  - National convention 1931 Richmond, Virginia, 4 folders (Box 4)
  - State convention 1931 Marquette (Box 4)
  - North-Central regional conference 1932 St. Paul, Minnesota (Box 4)
  - State convention 1932 Kalamazoo (Box 4)
  - National convention 1933 Chicago (Box 4)
  - State convention 1933 Detroit (Box 4)
  - North-Central regional conference 1934 Grand Rapids, Michigan (Box 4)
  - National convention 1935 Seattle, Washington (Box 4)
  - State convention 1936 Sault Ste Marie (Box 4)
  - National convention 1937 Atlantic City, New Jersey (Box 4)
  - State convention 1938 Detroit (Box 4)
  - North-Central regional convention 1940 Madison, Wisconsin (Box 4)
  - State convention 1940 Grand Rapids (Box 4)
  - State convention 1942 Bay City (Box 4)
  - National convention 1963 Dallas, Texas (Box 4)
  - National convention 1965 Washington, D.C. (Box 4)
  - National convention 1966 Atlanta, Georgia (Box 4)
- Photographs, 1925-1929, 1972-1986, and undated
  - Miscellaneous photographs (Box 4)
  - Photographs 1925 Portland, Maine convention (also UBKl) (Box 4)
  - Photographs 1927 Oakland, California convention (Box 4)
  - Photographs 1929 Mackinac Island, Michigan convention (Box 4)
  - Photograph album: convention and awards photos 1972-1986 (Box 4)
  - Album 1973-1985 (Box 4)
- Scrapbooks, 1920s-1980s
  - Various dates, 1 folders; 3 volumes (Box 4)
  - 1920s-1980s, 4 volumes (Box 5)
  - 1920s-1980s, 4 volumes (Box 6)
    (continued)